I am failing as a feminist.
وأفشل كمناصرة للنساء.
I have passionate opinions about gender equality,
ولدي آراء عاطفية حول المساواة بين الجنسين،
but I worry that to freely accept the label of "feminist,"
ولكن أخشى إذا وافقت على وصفي "بمناصرة النساء"،
I'm a feminist, but I'm a rather bad one.
أنا مناصرة للنساء، ولكن مناصرة سيئة.
Oh, so I call myself a Bad Feminist.
لذلك أدعو نفسي بالمناصرة السيئة.
Or at least, I wrote an essay,
أو على الأقل، كتبت مقالًا،
and then I wrote a book called "Bad Feminist,"
وبعدها كتاباً بعنوان "مناصرة النساء السيئة"
and then in interviews, people started calling me The Bad Feminist.
وبعدها في المقابلات، بدأ الناس ينادونني بالمناصرة السيئة للنساء.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So, what started as a bit of an inside joke with myself
لذا، ما بدأ كمجرد مزحة مع نفسي
and a willful provocation,
واستفزاز مقصود،
has become a thing.
تحول إلى شيء.
Let me take a step back.
دعوني أعود قليلًا للوراء.
When I was younger,
عندما كنت أصغر سنًا،
mostly in my teens and 20s,
خلال سن المراهقة والعشرينيات،
I had strange ideas about feminists
كانت لدي أفكار غريبة عن مناصرات النساء
as hairy, angry, man-hating, sex-hating women --
أنهن نساء ذوات شعر، غاضبات، كارهات للرجل، كارهات للجنس --
as if those are bad things.
وكأنها أمور سيئة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
These days, I look at how women are treated the world over,
واليوم، أنظر إلى الكيفية التي تُعامل بها النساء حول العالم،
and anger, in particular, seems like a perfectly reasonable response.
وشعور الغضب، على وجه التحديد، يبدو أنه رد الفعل الطبيعي الملائم.
But back then,
ولكن في ذلك الوقت،
I worried about the tone people used
ركزت على النبرة التي يستخدمها الناس
when suggesting I might be a feminist.
عندما كانوا يفترضون أني قد أكون مناصرة للنساء.
The feminist label was an accusation,
وقد كان وصف مناصرة للنساء يعتبر اتهامًا،
it was an "F" word, and not a nice one.
فقد كانت كلمة محظورة، ولم تكن لطيفة.
I was labeled a woman who doesn't play by the rules,
وصفتُ بأني امرأة لا تلعب وفقًا للقواعد،
who expects too much,
التي تتوقع كثيرًا جدًا،
who thinks far too highly of myself,
وتفكر بنفسها بشكل مبالغ فيه للغاية،
by daring to believe I'm equal -- (Coughs) -- superior to a man.
بالتجرأ على الإيمان أنها مساوية أو متفوقة على الرجل.
You don't want to be that rebel woman,
لا تريدين أن تكوني تلك المتمردة،
until you realize that you very much are that woman,
حتى تدركي أنكِ تلك المرأة،
and cannot imagine being anyone else.
ولا يمكنك تخيل أن تكوني أي شخص آخر.
As I got older, I began to accept
وعندما كبرتُ، بدأت قبول
that I am, indeed, a feminist, and a proud one.
أني مناصرة فعلًا للنساء، ومناصرة فخورة.
I hold certain truths to be self-evident:
أتمسك بحقائق محددة لتكون من البديهيات:
Women are equal to men.
النساء متساويات مع الرجال.
We deserve equal pay for equal work.
نحن نستحق أجرًا متساويًا للعمل المتساوي.
We have the right to move through the world as we choose,
لدينا الحق في التنقل عبر العالم كما نختار،
free from harassment or violence.
وأن لا نعاني من التحرش أو العنف.
We have the right to easy, affordable access to birth control,
لدينا الحق في طريقة سهلة وبالمتناول لتحديد النسل،
and reproductive services.
وخدمات الصحة الإنجابية.
We have the right to make choices about our bodies,
لدينا الحق في اتخاذ قرارات حول أجسادنا،
free from legislative oversight or evangelical doctrine.
خالية من الرقابة التشريعية أو المذهب الإنجيلي.
We have the right to respect.
لدينا الحق في الاحترام.
There's more.
و هناك مزيد.
When we talk about the needs of women,
عندما نتحدث عن احتياجات المرأة،
we have to consider the other identities we inhabit.
علينا أن ننظر بعين الاعتبار إلى الهويات الأخرى التي نعيشها.
We are not just women.
نحن لسنا نساء فقط.
We are people with different bodies,
نحن بشر أجسامنا وسماتنا الجنسية
gender expressions, faiths, sexualities,
وأقدارنا ونشاطاتنا الجنسية وخلفياتنا الاجتماعية،
class backgrounds, abilities, and so much more.
وقدراتنا مختلفة، وأكثر من ذلك بكثير.
We need to take into account
ونحن بحاجة إلى أن نضع في الحسبان
these differences and how they affect us,
هذه الاختلافات وكيفية تأثيرها علينا،
as much as we account for what we have in common.
بقدر ما نضع في الحسبان القواسم المشتركة بيننا.
Without this kind of inclusion, our feminism is nothing.
من دون هذا النوع من الشمول فإن مناصرتنا للنساء لا تساوي شيئًا.
I hold these truths to be self-evident, but let me be clear:
أنا أؤمن بأن هذه الحقائق بديهية، ولكن دعوني أوضح:
I'm a mess.
أنا في حالة من الفوضى.
I am full of contradictions.
أنا مليئة بالتناقضات.
There are many ways in which I'm doing feminism wrong.
هناك العديد من الطرق الخاطئة التي أناصر بها النساء.
I have another confession.
لدي اعتراف آخر.
When I drive to work, I listen to thuggish rap at a very loud volume.
عندما أقود سيارتي للعمل، استمع إلى الراب العدواني بصوت عال جدًا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Even though the lyrics are degrading to women --
على الرغم من أن الكلمات مهينة للنساء -
these lyrics offend me to my core --
هذه كلمات تسيء لي بالصميم -
the classic Yin Yang Twins song "Salt Shaker" --
كلاسيكية يين يانغ توينز أغنية "رشاشة الملح" -
it is amazing.
إنها رائعة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"Make it work with your wet t-shirt.
"أثيريني بتيشيرتك الرطب.
Bitch, you gotta shake it 'til your camel starts to hurt!"
يا عاهرة، يجب عليكي أن تهزي حتى تؤلمك عانتك!"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Think about it.
فكر في الأمر.
Poetry, right?
شعر، أليس كذلك؟
I am utterly mortified by my music choices.
أنا أشهر بخزي تمامًا بخيارات موسيقاي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I firmly believe in man work,
وأعتقد جازمًة في عمل الرجل،
which is anything I don't want to do, including --
وهو أي شيء لا أريد القيام به، بما في ذلك -
(Laughter) --
(ضحك) -
all domestic tasks,
كل المهام المنزلية،
but also: bug killing, trash removal, lawn care and vehicle maintenance.
ولكن أيضا: التخلص من الحشرات وإزالة القمامة ورعاية الحديقة وصيانة المركبات.
I want no part of any of that.
لا أريد جزءًا من أي ذلك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Pink is my favorite color.
الوردي هو لوني المفضل.
I enjoy fashion magazines and pretty things.
أستمتع بمجلات الموضة والأشياء الجميلة.
I watch "The Bachelor" and romantic comedies,
أشاهد "العازب" والمسلسلات الرومانسية الكوميدية،
and I have absurd fantasies about fairy tales coming true.
ولدي أوهام سخيفة حول تحقق الحكايات الخيالية.
Some of my transgressions are more flagrant.
بعض من معاصيي صارخة أكثر .
If a woman wants to take her husband's name,
إذا أرادت المرأة أن تأخذ اسم زوجها،
that is her choice, and it is not my place to judge.
هذا هو خيارها، وليس من حقي الحكم.
If a woman chooses to stay home to raise her children,
إذا اختارت المرأة البقاء في المنزل لتربية أطفالها،
I embrace that choice, too.
أتبنى هذا الخيار أيضًا.
The problem is not that she makes herself economically vulnerable in that choice;
المشكلة ليست في أنها تجعل من نفسها ضعيفة اقتصاديًا بهذا الاختيار.
the problem is that our society is set up
المشكلة هي أن مجتمعنا أسس
to make women economically vulnerable when they choose.
لجعل النساء معرضة للهجوم اقتصادياً عندما تختار ذلك .
Let's deal with that.
دعونا التعامل مع ذلك.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
I reject the mainstream feminism
أنا أرفض تعميم النسوية
that has historically ignored or deflected the needs
التي تجاهلت تاريخيا أو حيدت احتياجات
of women of color, working-class women, queer women and transgender women,
ذوات البشرة الملونة أو من الطبقة العاملة، النساء المعتلة و المتحولات جنسيا،
in favor of supporting white, middle- and upper-class straight women.
لصالح دعم النساء البيض، والنساء من الطبقة المتوسطة والعليا .
Listen, if that's good feminism -- I am a very bad feminist.
اسمعوني، وإذا كانت هذه هي النسوية الجيدة - فأنا نسوية سيئة للغاية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
There is also this:
وهناك أيضا شيء آخرا:
As a feminist, I feel a lot of pressure.
فكمناصرة للمرأة، أشعر بالكثير من الضغط.
We have this tendency to put visible feminists on a pedestal.
حيث أنه لدينا ميول لوضع المناصرات للمرأة تحت المجهر
We expect them to pose perfectly.
ونحن نتوقع منهم أن يتصرفوا بمثالية ،
When they disappoint us,
وعندما يخيبن أملنا ،
we gleefully knock them from the very pedestal we put them on.
نطيح بهم بعنف بنفس القدر الذي كنا نمتدحهم فيه بالبداية
Like I said, I am a mess --
كما قلت، وأنا في حالة من الفوضى -
consider me knocked off that pedestal
وتأملوا معي الإطاحة بهذا التمثال
before you ever try to put me up there.
قبل أن تحاولوا أصلاً رفعه ومدحه .
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Too many women,
الكثير من النساء،
particularly groundbreaking women and industry leaders,
ولا سيما النساء الرائدات وقادة الصناعة،
are afraid to be labeled as feminists.
يخافن من وصفهن كمناصرات للمرأة ،
They're afraid to stand up and say, "Yes, I am a feminist,"
إنهن خشين أن يقفن ليقلن : "نعم، أنا مناصرة للمرأة"
for fear of what that label means,
خوفاً من ما تعني هذه التسمية،
for fear of being unable to live up to unrealistic expectations.
خوفا من عدم القدرة على الارتقاء إلى مستوى توقعات غير واقعية.
Take, for example, Beyoncé, or as I call her, The Goddess.
خذ على سبيل المثال،المغنية بيونسيه، أو كما أسميها أنا معبودة الجماهير.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
She has emerged, in recent years, as a visible feminist.
لقد برزت في السنوات الأخيرة، كمناصرة قوية للمرأة.
At the 2014 MTV Video Music Awards,
وفي جوائز ال MTV للموسيقى في عام 2014
she performed in front of the word "feminist" 10 feet high.
تم تكريمها كمناصرة للمرأة على مرأى من العالم.
It was a glorious spectacle to see
لقد كان مشهداً تمجيدياً
this pop star openly embracing feminism
نجمة البوب هذه بكل وضوح تبنت قضية مناصرة المرأة
and letting young women and men know
والسماح للنساء والشبان بأن يعرفوا
that being a feminist is something to celebrate.
بأن مناصرة المرأة شيء يستحق الاحتفال
As the moment faded, cultural critics began endlessly debating
عندما تتلاشى اللحظة والنقد الثقافي يبدأ المناقشة التي لا تنتهي بخصوص
whether or not Beyoncé was, indeed, a feminist.
إن كانت بيونسيه مناصرة للمرأة أم لا.
They graded her feminism,
تم تصنيف مناصرتها للمرأة
instead of simply taking a grown, accomplished woman at her word.
على أنها ناضجة بدلاً من أن يتم وصفها على أنها إمرأة حققت إنجازاً
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
We demand perfection from feminists,
نحن نطالب الكمال من المناصرات للمرأة ،
because we are still fighting for so much,
لأننا ما زلنا نكافح من أجل الكثير،
we want so much,
نريد كثيرًا،
we need so damn much.
نحتاج الى الكثير الكثير ...
We go far beyond reasonable, constructive criticism,
لنذهب إلى ما هو وراء المنطق والنقد البناء ،
to dissecting any given woman's feminism,
لنحلل بدقة أي إمرأة مناصرة لقضايا المرأة
tearing it apart until there's nothing left.
نحللها بعمق حت لا يبقى شيء .
We do not need to do that.
نحن لسنا بحاجة للقيام بذلك.
Bad feminism -- or really, more inclusive feminism -- is a starting point.
مناصرة المرأة السيئة أو حتى شمولية هذه القضية هي نقطة البداية
But what happens next?
ولكن ماذا الذي يحدث بعد ذلك؟
We go from acknowledging our imperfections to accountability,
نقوم بالإعتراف بخللنا بالمساءلة ،
or walking the walk, and being a little bit brave.
أو أن نكون أكثر شجاعة من ذلك .
If I listen to degrading music,
فإذا كنت تستمع إلى الموسيقى المهينة ،
I am creating a demand for which artists are more than happy
فلقد قمت بزيادة الطلب عليها مما يجعل هؤلاء الفنانين في غاية السعادة
to contribute a limitless supply.
ومساعدتهم في إصدار أعداد غير محدودة
These artists are not going to change
هؤلاء الفنانين لن يتغيروا
how they talk about women in their songs
بطريقة تحدثهم عن النساء في أغانيهم
until we demand that change by affecting their bottom line.
إلا إذا قمنا بمطالبتهم بتغير الكلمات
Certainly, it is difficult.
بالتأكيد،هذا صعب.
Why must it be so catchy?
لماذا يجب أن يكون جذابا جدا؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It's hard to make the better choice,
من الصعب الوصول إلى الخيار الأفضل
and it is so easy to justify a lesser one.
وأنه من السهل جدا تبرير ذلك
But --
ولكن -
when I justify bad choices,
عندما أبرر الخيارات السيئة ،
I make it harder for women to achieve equality,
أجعل من الصعب على النساء تحقيق المساواة
the equality that we all deserve,
المساواة التي نستحقها جميعاً،
and I need to own that.
وأنا بحاجة للوصول إليها .
I think of my nieces, ages three and four.
أفكر في بنات أختي اللاتي تتراوح أعمارهن بين ثلاثة وأربعة سنوات
They are gorgeous and headstrong, brilliant girls,
وهن فتيات رائعات وجميلات،
who are a whole lot of brave.
ويمتلكن الكثير من الشجاعة .
I want them to thrive in a world where they are valued
أريد أن أراهن يزدهرن ويعيشن في مجتمع يقوم بمعرفة قيمتهن
for the powerful creatures they are.
وقيمة القوى الكامنىة بداخلهن.
I think of them,
أفكر فيهن،
and suddenly, the better choice becomes far easier to make.
وفجأة،يصبح تحقيق الخيار الأفضل أسهل بكثير.
We can all make better choices.
حيث يمكننا جميعاً أن نقوم بخيارات أفضل ،
We can change the channel when a television show
يمكننا تغيير القناة عندما يقوم التلفزيون بعرض
treats sexual violence against women like sport,
مشاهد عنف جنسية ضد المراة مثل الرياضة،
Game of Thrones.
ومسلسل"جايمز أوف ثرونز".
We can change the radio station
يمكننا تغيير محطة الراديو
when we hear songs that treat women as nothing.
عندما نسمع الأغاني التي تعامل المرأة على أنها شيء.
We can spend our box office dollars elsewhere
يمكننا أن ننفق دولاراتنا في مكان آخر
when movies don't treat women
حين تتعامل الأفلام مع المرأة
as anything more than decorative objects.
كما لو أنها لم تكن أكثر من مجرد قطعة ديكور.
We can stop supporting professional sports
يمكننا التوقف عن دعم الرياضة المهنية
where the athletes treat their partners like punching bags.
حيث يعامل الرياضيين شركائهم باللعب كما لو كانوا أكياس مخصصة للكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
In other ways, men -- and especially straight white men --
بعبارة أخرى ،الرجال وبالأخص الرجال البيض الرشيقين
can say, "No, I will not publish with your magazine,
يمكنهم القول، "لا، أنا لن أقوم بالنشر على مجلاتكم ،
or participate in your project, or otherwise work with you,
أو المشاركة في مشروعكم ، أو أي عمل آخر معكم
until you include a fair number of women,
حتى تشملوا عدداً لا بأس به من النساء،
both as participants and decision makers.
سواءً كمشاركات وكمتخذات للقرارات.
I won't work with you until your publication,
وأنا لن أعمل معكم حتى يكون منشوركم
or your organization, is more inclusive of all kinds of difference."
أو مؤسستكم، أكثر شمولاً لجميع أنواع الاختلاف".
Those of us who are underrepresented
وأن نجعل أولئك الأقل منا
and invited to participate in such projects,
يشاركون في مثل هذه المشاريع،
can also decline to be included
ويمكن أيضا أن ترفض المشاركة
until more of us are invited through the glass ceiling,
حتى يتم دعوة الكثير منا من خلال السقف الزجاجي
and we are tokens no more.
وكأننا رموزلا أكثر .
Without these efforts,
بدون هذه الجهود،
without taking these stands,
وبدون اتخاذ هذه المواقف،
our accomplishments are going to mean very little.
ستكون إنجازاتنا قليلة.
We can commit these small acts of bravery
يمكننا القيام بمثل هذه الأفعال الصغيرة الشجاعة
and hope that our choices trickle upward to the people in power --
ونأمل أن تصل خياراتنا الى أصحاب السلطة --
editors, movie and music producers,
والمحررين، ومنتجي الموسيقى والأفلام ،
CEOs, lawmakers --
كبار المدراء التنفيذيين والمشرعين --
the people who can make bigger, braver choices
الناس الذين يمكنهم القيام بخيارات كبيرة وشجاعة
to create lasting, meaningful change.
لخلق تغير دائم ذي معنى .
We can also boldly claim our feminism --
يمكننا أيضاً أن نصف بشجاعة مناصرتنا للمرأة --
good, bad, or anywhere in between.
سواء كانت جيدة، سيئة، أو ما بين بين.
The last line of my book "Bad Feminist" says,
السطر الأخير من كتابي "المناصرون السيئون للمرأة "يقول :
"I would rather be a bad feminist than no feminist at all."
"أفضل أن أكون مناصرة سيئة للمرأة من عدم مناصرتي لها على الإطلاق."
This is true for so many reasons,
وهذا صحيح لأسباب عديدة،
but first and foremost, I say this because once upon a time,
ولكن أولاً وقبل كل شيء، وأنا أقول هذا لأنه كان يا مكان ،
my voice was stolen from me,
حدث أن سرق مني صوتي،
and feminism helped me to get my voice back.
وساعدتني قضية مناصرة المرأة برجوع صوتي.
There was an incident.
كان هناك حادث.
I call it an incident so I can carry the burden of what happened.
أسميه حادث حتى أنه يمكنني تحمل ما حدث.
Some boys broke me,
كسرني بعض الأولاد ،
when I was so young, I did not know
عندما كنت صغيرة جدا، لم أكن أعرف
what boys can do to break a girl.
ما يمكن للأولاد القيام به لكسر فتاة،
They treated me like I was nothing.
عاملوني وكأنني لا شيء.
I began to believe I was nothing.
بدأت أعتقد أنني لا شيء.
They stole my voice, and in the after,
سرقوا صوتي، وفي مابعد،
I did not dare to believe
لم أكن أجرؤ على الاعتقاد
that anything I might say could matter.
أن أي شيء يمكن أن أقوله سيكون مهماً
But --
ولكن -
I had writing.
كانت لدي موهبة الكتابة
And there, I wrote myself back together.
وهناك، جمعت قواي مرة أخرى.
I wrote myself toward a stronger version of myself.
كتبت نفسي نحو نسخة أقوى من نفسي.
I read the words of women
قرأت كلام النساء
who might understand a story like mine,
الذين يمكن لهن أن يفهمن قصة كقصتي ،
and women who looked like me,
والنساء اللاتي يشبهنني،
and understood what it was like to move through the world with brown skin.
وفهمت ماذا يعني أن تتحرك في العالم وأنت ذو بشرة داكنة.
I read the words of women who showed me I was not nothing.
قرأت كلام النساء اللاتي أظهرن لي أنني لم أكن مجرد شيء ،
I learned to write like them,
تعلمت أن أكتب مثلهن،
and then I learned to write as myself.
وبعد ذلك تعلمت أن أكتب كما عليه أنا
I found my voice again,
لقد وجدت صوتي مرة أخرى،
and I started to believe that my voice is powerful beyond measure.
وبدأت أعتقد أن صوتي قوي لا قياس له.
Through writing and feminism,
من خلال الكتابة ومناصرة المرأة ،
I also found that if I was a little bit brave,
كما أنني وجدت أنه إذا كنت شجاعة قليلاً،
another woman might hear me and see me and recognize
امرأة أخرى قد تسمعني وتراني وتعترف
that none of us are the nothing the world tries to tell us we are.
بأنه على عكس ما حاول العالم إخبارنا به فلا أحد منا يعتبر لاشيء.
In one hand,
بيد واحدة،
I hold the power to accomplish anything.
وصلت للقوة لإنجاز أي شيء.
And in my other,
وفي بعضي الاخر،
I hold the humbling reality that I am just one woman.
وصلت لتقدير الواقع المتواضع بأنني فقط مجرد إمرأة ،
I am a bad feminist,
أنا مناصرة سيئة للنساء ،
I am a good woman,
ولكني امرأة جيدة،
I am trying to become better in how I think,
أحاول أن أرتقي بطريقة تفكيري،
and what I say, and what I do,
وقولي وفعلي،
without abandoning everything that makes me human.
دون التخلي عن كل ما يجعلني إنسانة.
I hope that we can all do the same.
آمل أن نتمكن كلنا من القيام بذلك .
I hope that we can all be a little bit brave,
من أن نكون شجعانا قليلاً،
when we most need such bravery.
عندما نكون بأمس الحاجة إلى مثل هذه الشجاعة.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)